Jean-Charles Quillet

13, rue du clos romain, 35120 Dol-de-Bretagne, FRANCE

🛮 (+33) 6-65-13-50-75 | 💌 jeancharles.quillet@gmail.com | 🧥 jeancharles.quillet.org | 🖸 jecaro | 🛅 jeancharlesquillet

Summary.

I am a software developer with a large experience in very diverse fields. I have worked as a backend developer, have wrote desktop applications, simulation software as well as network servers.

I have had the chance to work with low level object-oriented programming such as C++ which I have used professionally for more than ten years, and also with very high level functional programming languages such as Haskell. Theses different approaches give me a good comprehension of the mechanisms at work in software development, always driven by the goal of developing correct, safe and robust software.

Skills

Main skills: Architecture and software design

Functional programming Object oriented programming

Networking / Linux systems administration

Geographic information systems Geometry and 3D rendering

Operating systems: Windows, Linux (NixOS, ArchLinux, Ubuntu, CentOS, Debian)

Programming languages: Haskell, Elm, C/C++, nix, Python, Bash

Development tools/Continuous integration: GNU make, GIT, SVN, gprof, Jenkins, Travis, Ansible, Docker

Scientific tools: Matlab, Octave, gnuplot

Languages: French: mother tongue, English: fluent, Espagnol: beginner

Experience

Secucloud Hamburg, Germany / Remote

CLOUD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Since 11/2020

- · Development of network security software in a cloud architecture
- International team, full time remote
- Technical environment: Linux, Haskell, nix, Ansible, Clickhouse

Epitech Rennes

FUNCTIONAL PROGRAMMING TEACHER

09/2021 - 06/2023 (part time)

- Supporting the students with their Haskell projects (Arithmetic expression evaluator, List interpretor, image compression algorithm ...)
- Technical environment: Linux, Haskell, nix

Scalian Rennes

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER FOR A SUBCONTRACTOR COMPANY

04/2007 - 11/2020

- Developing simulation software in the department Simulation, HPC and Virtual Reality
- Architecture and technical lead
- · Technical documentation writing
- Clients: french MoD, ONERA, CEA, CNES, IRSN
- Technical environment: Windows/Linux, C++, Python, Matlab, Qt, openscenegraph, gdal

LaBRI Analysis and indexing video team (University lab)

Bordeaux

07/2006 - 08/2006

09/2004 - 04/2006

• Prepared the video indexing contests TRECVID and ARGOS

System administration

RESEARCH ENGINEER

RESEARCH ENGINEER

• Technical environment: Linux, C/C++, XML, Perl, Bash, SVN

INRIA IPARLA team (French IT lab)

Rordeaux

1

• Visualization of city models on mobile devices thought non-photorealistic rendering

- Writing and presenting a scientific paper to the Web3D 2006 conference in Washington
- Technical environment: Linux, Windows, Windows Mobile, C/C++, Bash, Perl, VRML97, X3D, CVS

CV REALIZED WITH LATEX BASED ON THE MODEL AWESOME CV

Keyghost Christchurch, New-Zealand

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

04/2003 - 12/2003

- Development of security software
- Technical environment: Windows, Delphi, C/C++, Octave

Visualpix Bordeaux

INTERNSHIP FOLLOWED BY A SOFTWARE ENGINEER CONTRACT

- Improved a video compression codec
- Technical environment: Linux, C, CVS

Glisshouse Marseille

BACKEND DEVELOPER, SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

07/2000 - 03/2001

04/2002 - 12/2002

- Web: Maintained an online shop, developed a CMS
- System administration: Installed, setup and maintained LAN (router, DNS, firewall, proxy, backup management, file server, print server)
- Technical environment: Linux, Php, MySQL, Apache, Samba, cron

Education

2001 - 2002	DESS Multimedia and Information Technology, Image synthesis and	Bordeaux university
	analysis, 3D geometry and rendering, sound, video	
1999 - 2000	Master in computer science, Option image synthesis	Poitiers university
1998 - 1999	B.S. in computer science	Limoges university
1996 - 1997	DEUG computer science and mathematics	Limoges university
1995 - 1996	Baccalauréat Science	Lycée Jean Giraudoux, Châteauroux

Extracurricular Activity

Sports: Rock climbing, bike commuting, surf, trekking

Culture: Literature (classical, travel, adventure), cinema, attending rock concerts, guitar playing

Community commitments: Member of the direction comity of the rock climbing club of Rennes (2012 to 2016)

Volunteered at concert venues of Rennes: Antipode (2011 to 2015), le Jardin Moderne (2009 to 2010)

Volunteered to the music festivals Epipapu (2009, 2010) and la Route du Rock (2008 - 2018)

Travel: New-Zealand, Australia, USA, Canada, Malaysia, Bali, Bolivia, Iceland, Norway, Scotland, Faroe Islands